...or never give a saga an even break!
Blazing Saddles is a western, comedy film directed by Mel Brooks.
A town—where everyone seems to be named
Johnson—stands in the way of the railroad.
In order to grab their land, robber baron Hedley Lamarr sends
his henchmen to make life in the town unbearable.
After the sheriff is killed, the town demands a new sheriff from the Governor, so
Hedley convinces him to send the town the first black sheriff in the west.
Bart, played by Cleavon Little.
Jim, played by Gene Wilder.
Taggart, played by Slim Pickens.
Hedley Lamarr, played by Harvey Korman.
Lili Von Shtupp, played by Madeline Kahn.
Governor William J. Le Petomane / Indian Chief, played by Mel Brooks.
Blazing Saddles is a 1974 American satirical postmodernist Western comedy film directed by Mel Brooks, who co-wrote the
screenplay with Andrew Bergman, Richard Pryor, Norman Steinberg and Alan Uger, based on a story treatment by Bergman.
The film stars Cleavon Little and Gene Wilder.
Brooks appears in two supporting roles: Governor William J.
Le Petomane, and a Yiddish-speaking Native American chief; he also dubs lines for
one of Lili Von Shtupp's backing troupe and a cranky moviegoer.
The supporting cast includes Slim Pickens, Alex Karras and David Huddleston, as
well as Brooks regulars Dom DeLuise, Madeline Kahn and Harvey Korman.
Bandleader Count Basie has a cameo as himself, appearing with his orchestra.
The film is full of deliberate anachronisms, from the Count Basie Orchestra playing "April in
Paris" in the Wild West, to Pickens' character mentioning the Wide World of Sports.
Blazing Saddles was released by Warner Bros.
on February 7, 1974.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and audiences, was nominated for three Academy Awards and
is today regarded as a comedy classic, while grossing $119.6 million against a $2.6 million budget.
It is ranked number six on the American Film Institute's 100 Years...100 Laughs list, and was deemed "culturally, historically, or
aesthetically significant" by the Library of Congress and was selected for preservation in the National Film Registry in 2006.
The film explores themes of governor, saloon, gun, parody, marching band.
The tone is lighthearted.